Okay, so let's begin class.
好的，开始上课。
And today we are discussing whether or not Trump will win in November.
今天我们讨论特朗普是否会在十一月赢得选举。
And I'm making the prediction that he will win in November
我预测他会在十一月赢得选举。
and that
以及那点
he will pick Nikki Haley as his vice president.
他将挑选尼基·海利为副总统。
Okay, so let me make you the argument today.
好了，接下来我给你们讲个论点。
Okay, so let's first discuss why Biden won in 2020
好的，先来讨论一下拜登在2020年赢得选举的原因。
and why it's possible
然后再说说今年他可能会输的可能性。
that he may lose this year.
（此处可补充）
Okay, so in 2020,
好的，2020年是……
it was a very special year in American politics
那一年美国政治格局特别特殊……
because it was a larger,
因为投票人数比往年多……
it was the largest turnout in American history since about 1900.
自1900年以来，美国历史上最大的投票率。
Okay, so 74 million people voted for Trump.
好，74万投票给特朗普。
For Biden, 81 million people voted for him.
81万投票给拜登。
And two out of every three American adults came out to vote.
并且每三位美国成年人中有两位投票。
Okay, so it was the largest turnout in American history.
好，2020年是美国历史上最大的投票率。
It doesn't, it sounds like a very lopsided victory for Biden,
听起来像是拜登的绝对大胜。
81 million versus 74 million.
8100万对比7400万。
But because America has an electoral college system,
但因为美国有选举团制度，
which is not director -elected,
它不是直接选举的。
it's not a democratic democracy, actually,
它并不是一次真正的民主投票，
the margin of victory was only 65,000 votes.
胜利差距仅有65,000票。
Meaning that if 65,000 people in key battleground states flipped their votes,
也就是说，如果关键摇摆州的65,000人投票翻转，
then Trump would have won.
然后特朗普就赢了。
Okay, so the margin of victory was very, very close,
好的，胜利差距非常非常接近，
as is usually the case in highly contested American elections.
正如在高度竞争的美国选举中常见的情况。
So let's understand the coalition that
于是我们来了解这个联盟
brought Biden into the White House.
把拜登送进白宫。
Okay, so
好的，所以。
the first major component of this coalition are black people.
第一大组成部分是黑人。
91% of all blacks voted for Biden.
91%的黑人投票给拜登。
Only 8% voted for Trump.
仅有8%投票给特朗普。
That's a huge majority for Biden.
这对拜登来说是大多数。
So why did so many black people vote for Biden in 2020?
那么，为什么那么多的黑人在2020年投票给拜登？
Well, first of all, it's because
首先，原因是……
Biden was Obama's vice president for eight years.
拜登曾是奥巴马的副总统八年。
And so a lot of older black people had a certain loyalty to him.
于是很多年长的黑人对他有一定的忠诚。
Okay, they felt that we owe this man because
好的，他们觉得我们欠这位先生，因为
he served loyally to our man, Barack Obama, for eight years.
他忠诚地为我们的男人巴拉克·奥巴马服务了八年。
And so now we must bring him into the White House.
于是现在我们必须把他带进白宫。
But this year, the debt is paid off, right?
但今年债务已付清，对吗？
So they won't feel so loyal to Biden.
于是他们对拜登的忠诚度就不那么高了。
Okay. Also in 2020,
好的。还有在2020年，
there's something called a George Floyd protest.
有个叫做“乔治·弗洛伊德”抗议的事。
So what happened was that
于是发生的事是这样：
in May 2020,
2020年5月，
a black man in Minneapolis, George Floyd,
明尼阿波利斯的黑人乔治·弗洛伊德
he was strangled to death by a white police officer.
他被一名白人警察扼住喉咙致死。
It was captured on video and it caused a national uproar.
它被拍成视频并引发全国性骚乱。
In fact, there were riots
实际上，发生了骚乱
and protests throughout the country.
并在全国掀起示威。
And Trump came out and did this.
随后特朗普出现并这么做了。
He did not acknowledge the pain that
他没有承认那份痛感
black people felt because of this death.
黑人因这起死亡事件而产生感受。
And so black people felt antipathy towards Trump. Okay.
于是黑人对特朗普产生了反感。好的。
So these are the two major reasons why black people voted for Biden in 2020.
所以这两点是黑人在2020年投票给拜登的主要原因。
But this year,
但今年，
Trump's not in office, right?
特朗普已经不在任了，对吗？
Biden's in office. So black people are asking the question,
拜登在任。于是黑人们在问……
what has Biden done for us these past four years?
拜登过去四年为我们做了什么？
And unfortunately, the answer is not that much.
不幸的是，答案并不多。
And in fact, you can make the argument that
而且，你可以这样论证：
Biden has really hurt the standard of living of black people.
拜登确实让黑人生活水平下降。
Why? Because inflation has gone up.
为什么？因为通胀上涨了。
Okay. When inflation goes up,
好的。当通胀上涨时，
it usually hurts poor people the most.
它通常最伤害的是贫困人群。
Okay. The standard of living goes way down.
好的，生活水平大幅下降。
Also, illegal immigration
另外，非法移民也在增加。好。
has gone up. Okay.
于是，在2020年，特朗普离任时。
So in 2020, when Trump left office,
So in 2020, whenTrump left office,
there were about 10 million illegal immigrants in America.
美国有大约一千万非法移民。
Now there are 20 million illegal immigrants in America.
现在美国有两千万非法移民。
And it seems like Biden's doing nothing to stop this trend.
看起来拜登什么也没做来阻止这个趋势。
And of course, when illegal immigrants come to the country,
当然，非法移民来到这个国家时，
they usually take the jobs of poor people.
他们通常抢走穷人的工作。
Okay. They bring wages down.
于是工资就下降了。
And that again hurts black people.
又一次又伤害了黑人。
And then third is Ukraine.
接着第三点是乌克兰。
So while the standard of living for black people
于是黑人生活水平下降。
and other poor people in America are going down,
以及美国其他贫困人群也在下降，
America is sending tens of billions of dollars to Ukraine to fight a war
美国向乌克兰拨出数百亿美元以作战斗，
that has nothing to do with America.
这与美国无关。
So many Americans see this as just bad leadership.
于是许多美国人把这看成只是糟糕的领导。
Okay. So that's black people.
好的。那就是黑人。
And recent polls show that
而最近的民调显示……
actually Biden's lead with black people is not a bad thing.
实际上拜登在黑人选民中的领先并不算坏事。
Not as much as it was in 2020.
比2020年少了不少。
Okay. So this lead is going down.
好的，这个领先正在下降。
Young people. Okay.
年轻人。好的。
Well, young people tend to vote Democratic in all elections.
嗯，年轻人往往在各次选举中投票给民主党。
And they were extremely galvanized to vote in 2020
他们在2020年投票热情高涨。
because they saw Trump as this very hateful racist
因为他们把特朗普视为极其可恨的种族主义者
that they must remove from office.
他必须从职务上移除。
Right. And they were driven to believe this because of the George Floyd protests.
对，正因乔治·弗洛伊德示威而产生此信念。
Unfortunately, this year,
不幸的是，今年，
young people may not feel compelled to vote for Biden.
年轻人可能不再被迫投票给拜登。
In fact, a lot of young people are choosing to sit out this election.
实际上，很多年轻人选择在这次选举中不投票。
Why? You guys know?
为什么？你们知道吗？
Gaza. Okay.
加沙。好的。
So as you know, right now,
所以正如你们所知，现在是……
throughout America on college campuses,
在美国各大专校园里，
young people are protesting the war in Gaza.
年轻人正在抗议加沙战争。
So these young people are not going to vote for Trump.
于是这些年轻人不会投票给特朗普。
Okay. But
好的。但
they probably will not vote for Biden as
他们大概不会投票给拜登，作为对美国通过以色列政策的抗议。
a protest against American policy via the Israel.
Okay. Now let's look at the college educated.
好的。现在我们来看看受过大学教育的人。
Okay. So 70% of people with college degrees voted for Biden.
好的。所以70%的大学学历者投票给拜登。
These are what we call the coastal elite.
这些就是我们所说的海岸精英。
Right. The coastal professional managerial elite.
右。海岸专业管理精英。
And they usually overwhelmingly vote Democratic.
他们通常压倒性投票给民主党。
And this year, they will still say the same.
今年他们仍会这么说。
But they will be less enthusiastic
但他们的热情会稍低
because of what they perceive to be poor global leadership.
因为他们认为全球领导力不足
Okay. Biden under Biden's watch, Ukraine blew up.
好的。拜登在位时，乌克兰爆炸
But so did Gaza.
但加沙也一样。
And many are starting to feel that it's because
而且许多人开始觉得这正是因为……
Biden comes across as too old,
拜登给人的印象太老了，
too weak, and too feeble to stand against Putin.
太弱，太脆弱，无法与普京抗衡。
Okay. So college educated people will still vote for Biden.
好的。所以受过大学教育的人仍会投票给拜登。
So overwhelmingly vote Democratic. That is the core Democratic base.
于是大多数投票给民主党。这就是核心民主党基础。
But they'll be less enthusiastic about Biden.
但他们对拜登的热情会稍低。
And they'll vote primarily against Trump.
他们主要会投票给普京。
Okay. Woman. Okay.
好的。女人。好的。
So 54% of women voted for Biden.
于是54%的女性投票给拜登。
44% voted for Trump.
44%投票给特朗普。
Okay. And again, because
好。再一次，因为
Trump is seen as this hateful figure.
特朗普被视为这位可恨的形象。
We expect that
我们预期它会。
woman will still consistently vote Democratic this year.
该女子今年仍将持续投票给民主党。
Okay. And also because of abortion issues.
好的。还有因为生育问题。
Right. So women are very passionate about abortion.
对。于是女性对生育问题非常热情。
And they will come out and vote for Biden to ensure
他们会出来投票给拜登以确保
that abortion rights are protected.
已保障生育权利。
Last, let's look at suburban voters.
最后，让我们看一下郊区选民。
Okay. So the suburbs.
好的。于是郊区。
The suburbs are between the cities, the urban areas, and the rural areas.
郊区位于城市、都市区与乡村之间。
Okay. Cities, urban areas, overwhelmingly support the Democratic Party.
好的。城市、都市区大多支持民主党。
Rural areas overwhelmingly support the Republican Party.
乡村区大多支持共和党。
So the suburbs are where the battleground is.
郊区就是战场所在。
And so if you look at 19,
于是如果你看2019年，
sorry, 2016,
抱歉，2016年。
when Trump defeated Hillary Clinton,
当特朗普击败希拉里·克林顿时
only 45% of
仅有45%的
the suburbs voted for Clinton.
郊区投票给克林顿
Which allowed Trump to defeat her in the election.
这使得特朗普在选举中击败她。
Okay. Now, what's interesting is that in 2020,
好的。接下来有趣的是在2020年，
this flipped and
这一点发生了翻转。
54% of suburban voters voted for Biden.
郊区选民中有54%投票给拜登。
That's a flip of 2 million voters.
这相当于两百万人投票翻转。
Okay. So in elections,
好，回到选举上。
usually it's a suburban vote that
通常是郊区选票决定选举，因为有摇摆选民。
determines the election because there's swing voters.
好的。于是我们来快速看看为什么。
Okay. So
for Trump to win this year,
为了让特朗普今年赢得胜利，
he needs to win the suburban vote.
他需要赢得郊区选票。
He won that in 2016.
他在2016年赢得了那一票。
He lost that in 2020. Okay.
他在2020年输了那一票。好了。
So let's examine very
于是我们来快速看看原因。
quickly why the
suburbs went Biden in 2020.
郊区在2020年投给拜登。
Okay. And there are three major reasons.
好的，还有三个主要原因。
The first is the media narrative. So
第一个是媒体叙事。
what's happening throughout Trump's presidency
特朗普执政期间发生的事
is basically the entire mainstream media got together
基本上，主流媒体聚在一起
and criticized Trump.
并批评特朗普。
Okay. So the first major criticism of Trump, if you remember,
好的。第一个主要批评是，若你记得，是他是俄国资产。
is he was a Russian asset.
Okay. He was a paid Putin puppet.
好的。他是付费的普京傀儡。
And of course, that was just a complete lie.
当然，那只是完全的谎言。
What we call Russiagate. Okay.
我们称之为俄案。好了。
But then they start to say that
但随后他们开始说……
Trump was a divisive figure.
特朗普是一个分裂的形象。
Okay. And
好的。
this idea caught
这个想法在郊区抓住了想象。
the imagination of the suburbs.
Okay. Because if you live in the suburbs, you tend to be middle class.
好的。因为如果你住在郊区，你往往属于中产阶层。
You tend to be pretty wealthy and well educated.
你往往会相当富裕且受过良好教育。
So you like the status quo. You want a leader who's conservative
于是你喜欢现状。你想要一个保守的领袖
and who's a unifier.
并且是个统一者
And throughout the Trump presidency, we saw that.
在整个特朗普任期里我们都看见了这一点
We saw the polarization of politics.
我们看到了政治的两极化。
The left and the right hate each other and they fought all the time.
左翼与右翼互相仇恨，时常争斗。
And what really showed this was the George Floyd protests.
而真正体现这一点的是乔治·弗洛伊德示威。
So you had protesters rioting in the streets.
于是街头有示威者起义。
And Trump was like, let's send in the military to crush the protesters.
于是特朗普说，派军队去镇压示威者。
And so people in the suburbs were very worried about this.
于是郊区的人对此很担心。
They thought that a leader, the president, should be a uniter.
他们认为，领袖、总统应是团结者。
Right. And Biden came across as extremely steady,
对，拜登给人极稳重之感，像个老牌人。
as very establishment, as someone who
他是个……
could unite both the Republican Party and the Democratic Party.
可以把共和党和民主党都团结起来。
Okay. That was his perception in 2020.
好的。那是他在2020年的看法。
So that's the first major reason why the suburbs went Biden.
这就是郊区投票给拜登的首要原因。
Second was the pandemic.
第二点是疫情。
So as you know, COVID hit the United States.
正如你所知，COVID席卷美国。
And the suburbs were extremely freaked out about this
郊区对此极为惊慌。
because they tend to have children who go to school.
因为他们往往有孩子上学。
They tend to be older.
他们往往年纪大。
And they thought that
他们认为这样就行了。
Trump's handling of the pandemic was very incompetent.
特朗普对疫情的处理非常不称职。
Okay. He was an outsider,
好的。他是个外来人，
a political outsider. But that meant he could not get things done in Washington.
但这意味着他在华盛办事不顺利。
Okay. So that's the second problem with Trump.
好的。那就是特朗普的第二个问题。
And the third reason why
还有第三个原因是
the suburbs went Biden is Kamala Harris.
郊区投给拜登的是卡玛拉·哈里斯。
Okay. And this is key.
好的。关键点来了。
Biden picked Kamala Harris to
拜登挑选卡玛拉·哈里斯为副总统。
be his vice president.
To be his running mate.
成为他的竞选搭档。
And Kamala Harris, let me tell you a little about Kamala Harris.
我来稍微介绍一下卡玛拉·哈里斯。
Her father is Jamaican.
她的父亲是牙买加人。
Her mother is Indian. And she has a younger sister.
她的母亲是印度人，她还有个妹妹。
But she was young.
但她还很年轻。
Her dad left the family.
她的父亲离开了家。
So her mom raised the two girls by herself.
她的妈妈独自抚养了这两个女孩。
And Kamala Harris is an extremely accomplished person.
卡玛拉·哈里斯是一位极为出色的人。
She went to Stanford.
她曾就读过斯坦福大学。
Then she became Attorney General of California.
然后她成为加利福尼亚州总检察长。
Then became a U.S.
随后她成为美国参议员。
Senator. Okay. And
好的。
there are three reasons why the suburbs love Kamala Harris.
有三个原因解释为什么郊区人喜欢卡玛拉·哈里斯。
Okay. First of all,
好的。首先，
like us.
像我们一样。
Okay. Meaning like she comes across as someone who
好的。也就是说她给人的印象是……
speaks and
说话像郊区人一样
thinks like people in the suburbs.
思考像郊区人一样
Okay. Well educated, articulate,
受过良好教育，口才好，聪明，保守。
smart, conservative.
Okay. Second is she's seen as very establishment.
好的。第二点是她被视为非常建制派。
Meaning that she's not liberal.
也就是说她不是自由派。
In fact, when she was Attorney General of California,
事实上，她在加州总检察官任期内，刑事案件处理非常严厉。
she was extremely tough on crime.
她在加州总检察官任期内，刑事案件处理非常严厉。
She was trying to send as many people to jail as possible.
她试着把尽可能多的人送进监狱。
And sometimes, quite honestly, some of these people were innocent.
有时，真诚地说，其中有些人是无辜的。
Okay. And she still sent them to jail.
好的。她还是把他们送进监狱。
She was very controversial as Attorney General.
她在加州总检察官任期内颇具争议。
But guess what, guys?
但你猜怎么了，伙计们？
People in the suburbs like tough on crime.
郊区的人喜欢对犯罪严厉。
Okay. They want safety.
好的。他们想要安全。
They want security. They have kids.
他们想要安全。孩子们在。
Okay. And
好的。
the third reason why they like Kamala Harris is
第三个他们喜欢卡玛拉·哈里斯的原因是
because of the redemption story.
因为复兴的故事。
So, in 2019,
于是，2019年，
there's a Democratic primary. Okay. This is when
有一次民主党初选。好的。那时
the Democrats try to
民主党人试图
get a nomination for the general election.
获得大选的提名。
Okay. And there was a lot of people who
好的，很多人争夺提名，包括乔·拜登和卡玛拉·哈里斯。
are vying for the nomination, including Joe Biden and Kamala Harris.
在2019年6月，
In June 2019,
there was the first Democratic debate.
有一次第一次民主党辩论。
Okay. And at this point, Kamala Harris and
好的。此时，卡玛拉·哈里斯和乔·拜登被视为夺得提名的重磅候选人。
Joe Biden were considered very heavy favorites to win the nomination.
And in that first debate,
在那场第一次辩论中，
Kamala Harris and Joe Biden got into a very serious fight.
卡玛拉·哈里斯和乔·拜登展开了一场激烈的争论。
And they had a very nasty argument on television.
他们在电视上争执得相当激烈。
Okay. So, what happened is that Kamala Harris turned to Joe Biden.
好的。于是，卡玛拉·哈里斯转向乔·拜登。
And Joe Biden is kind of shell -shocked.
乔·拜登有点像被震惊的样子。
Okay. He's kind of old.
好的。他有点老了。
And Kamala Harris is directing her words at him.
卡玛拉·哈里斯正把话说给他听。
And he doesn't really want to see her.
他并不想见她。
Okay. He doesn't really want to confront her.
他也不想跟她对峙。
And what Kamala Harris says to Joe Biden is,
凯玛拉·哈里斯对乔·拜登说，
Joe, you've been in Washington, D.C., for 50 years.
乔，你已经在华盛顿特区待了五十年。
And some of your policies I don't support.
而我不支持你的一些政策。
For example, you do not support the integration of black
例如，你不支持黑人融合
and white students together.
与白人学生一起。
Well, you know what, Joe?
好，乔，你知道吗？
I'm a black student.
我是黑人学生。
I was a black little girl, grew up in the 70s in California.
我是一名黑人小女孩，成长于70年代的加州。
And I got an opportunity to succeed in America
我在美国获得了成功的机会
because of integration, because I could go to white school.
因为融合，我可以去白人学校。
And you opposed my opportunity to succeed.
并且你阻碍了我的成功机会。
Okay. So, basically, she was calling.
好的。所以，基本上她在称呼。
She was calling Biden a racist.
她把拜登称为种族主义者。
And at that point, everyone thought that, okay, well, if Biden gets a nomination,
到那时，大家都认为，好的，嗯，如果拜登拿到提名，
there's no way he's going to pick her to be the VP.
他一定会把她选为副总统。
Okay. And then
好的。然后
he picks her to be the VP.
他挑选她为副总统。
And so what do people think about Biden?
那么人们对拜登的看法是什么？
What do people think of Biden?
人们对拜登的看法是什么？
What impression do people get because of this?
人们因这件事得到什么印象？
Anyone? Or there's no other impression or other
有人吗？或者没有其他印象，或者其他种类的印象。
sort of impression or other sort of impression.
还有其他种类的印象吗？
Or there's no other impression or other sort of impression or other sort of impression or other sort of impression or
other sort of impression or other sort of impression or impression or other sort of impression or other sort of impression
还有其他种类的印象吗？
or other sort of impression
或者其他种类的印象
or empathy
或者共情
okay he understands that voters want from
好的，他明白选民想要的
that Harris okay and
那哈里斯好的和
guess what guys these three things doesn't hold grudges listens team player
猜猜看，兄弟们，这三件事不留怨，听得懂，团队球员
and empathy this is anti -trump right this is the anti -trump
和共情，这才是反特朗普的，才是反特朗普的
and
和
because of this narrative
因为这个叙事
woman especially woman in the suburbs
尤其是郊区的女性
went for Biden okay previously
于是她们投给拜登
that gone for Trump now they went for Biden because
那时他们投给特朗普，现在又投给拜登，因为……
as it turns out woman want
结果是女性想要……
compassionate empathetic leadership that
有同情、同理的领导力
is decisive and bold
决定性且大胆
but is also
但也同样
tolerant okay and that this is also why even
宽容，且这也是原因
though Hillary Clinton what like ran in 2016 and
虽然希拉里·克林顿在2016年跑过一次并且
she was a woman the suburbs didn't vote for her
她是个女人，郊区没有投她
because she was she didn't come across as someone who
因为她没给人一种……
was a woman and she was a woman and she was a woman and she was a woman and she was compassionate and forgiving and
她是个女人，她是个女人，她是个女人，她是个女人，她是个女人，她很有同情心，很宽容，且…
tolerant okay does that make sense and
宽容，嗯，这样说对吗？
this is why Biden was
这就是为什么拜登是…
able to win in 2020
能在2020年赢得胜利
so
于是
this year what can Trump do
今年特朗普能做什么
to win the suburbs what can you do
赢得郊区，你能做什么
yeah he
是的，他
can copy this exact same thing okay and
他可以复制这同样的事
it turns out he can do this okay why because
结果他能做到这点，为什么呢？
on the Republican side there's someone not called
在共和党那边有个人，叫做…
Nikki Kelly Nikki Kelly I'm sorry Nikki Haley
尼基·凯利，尼基·凯利，我说的是尼基·海利
and
和
Nikki Haley is very similar
尼基·海利很相似
to Kamala Harris okay
像卡玛拉·哈里斯
Nikki Haley her parents are Indian immigrants okay
尼基·海利的父母是印度移民，没错。
so she's Indian she's of South Asian this descent
所以她是印度人，属于南亚裔。
and her father is a Muslim and she's a Muslim and
她父亲是穆斯林，她本人也是穆斯林。
she's a Muslim now there's a Muslim
她是穆斯林，现在有一个穆斯林
there's a Muslim there's a Muslim there's a Muslim there's a Muslim
有一个穆斯林，有一个穆斯林，有一个穆斯林，有一个穆斯林
there's a Muslim there's a Muslim there's a Muslim there's a Muslim there's a Muslim there's a Muslim there's a Muslim there's a Muslim there's a Muslim there's a Muslim
有一个穆斯林，有一个穆斯林，有一个穆斯林，有一个穆斯林，有一个穆斯林，有一个穆斯林，有一个穆斯林
there's a Muslim there's a Muslim there's a Muslim there's a Muslim there's a Muslim there's a Muslim there's a Muslim there's a Muslim there's
有一个穆斯林，有一个穆斯林，有一个穆斯林，有一个穆斯林，有一个穆斯林，有一个穆斯林，有一个穆斯林，有一个穆斯林，有一个
a Muslim there's a Muslim
有一个穆斯林，有一个穆斯林
there's a Muslim
有一个穆斯林
and even though
并且即便如此
she lost to Trump there was a group of people
她输给特朗普后，仍有一群人
who loved her guess who
他们喜欢她，猜测是……
just loved her who
刚刚喜欢她，猜测是……
voted for her in droves guess guess
投票给她的人在郊区猜测是……
what what demographic group anyone
什么什么人口群体……
sub -urban
郊区
woman okay you understand college educated suburban woman okay
大学教育的郊区女性，明白吧
so in other words if Trump brings her on to the ticket
换句话说，如果特朗普把她拉上车票
then
然后
it's very likely he can swing the suburbs back to him
他很可能把郊区重新拉回去
and win the election but
并赢得选举
there's a problem the problem is that
有个问题，问题是
Nikki Haley and
尼基·海利和
Trump got into a very nasty fight during the primary okay
特朗普在初选中打了一场很激烈的斗争
so Nikki Haley said listen I served under Trump
于是尼基·海利说：听着，我曾在特朗普手下服役
and I think he's going to win the election he's a divisive figure and
我认为他将赢得选举，他是个分裂人物，且现在我们的国家需要统一者
right now in our country we we need a unifier that's why I'm running for president
这就是我竞选总统的原因
because I want to unite this country whereas Trump can only divide this country okay
因为我想统一这个国家，而特朗普只能把它分裂。
and then Trump being Trump responds
随后，特朗普如常回应。
and says Nikki Haley is a birdbrain she's stupid okay
他说尼基·海利是个傻瓜，真是笨蛋。
so
于是
you think you see this you think like
你觉得你看到了这点，你会这样想
there's no way Trump will pick her because
没有办法让特朗普选她
Nikki Haley's not loyal to Trump right and Trump will pick her because she's a!
尼基·海利对特朗普不忠诚，特朗普会选她，因为她是个……！
И ему ему ему ему И
和他他他他和
ему ему ему И ему ему
他他他和他
ему И ему ему ему И ему ему ему И ему ему ему И ему ему ему
给他，给他他他，给他他他，给他他他
И ему ему ему И ему ему ему И ему ему ему И ему ему ему И
他他他他他
ему ему ему И ему ему ему И ему ему ему
他他他他
И ему ему ему И ему ему ему И ему ему И
他他他他…
ему ему И ему ему И ему ему И ему ему И ему ему И ему ему И
ему ему И ему
他他他
ему И ему ему
But let me ask you this question. If in August,
但请先问你一个问题。若在八月，
during the Republican convention,
在共和党大会期间，
he does pick Nikki Haley,
他确选尼基·海利
how would people feel about him?
人们会怎么感觉？
How would the media report this?
媒体会怎么报道这件事？
Nikki Haley is an enemy of Trump.
尼基·海利是特朗普的敌人。
Trump called her a bird brain.
特朗普称她是个傻瓜。
Trump said, I will never pick Nikki Haley.
特朗普说：我永远不会选尼基·海利。
And then in August, three months from now,
然后在八月，也就是三个月后
he says, you know what, I was wrong.
他说，知道了，我错了。
I think Nikki Haley is the best person to be my VP.
我认为尼基·海利是最合适合我的副总统人选。
That's why she'll be my running mate in November.
这就是她在十一月成为我的竞选搭档的原因。
How would people feel about him?
人们会怎么想他？
What would the suburbs think about Trump?
郊区人会怎么想特朗普？
How would you feel if you saw this?
如果你看到这个，你会怎么感觉？
Or you saw this now, or you saw this now, or you saw this now,
或者你现在看到这个，或者你现在看到这个，或者你现在看到这个，
or you saw this now.
或你现在看到这个。
Or you saw this now.
Or you saw this now. Or you saw this now.
或你现在看到这个。或你现在看到这个。
Or you saw this now.
或你现在看到这个。
Or you saw this now. Or you saw this now. Or you saw this now. Or you saw this now. Or you saw this now.
或你现在看到这个。或你现在看到这个。或你现在看到这个。或你现在看到这个。或你现在看到这个。
Or you saw this now. Or you saw this now.
或你现在看到这个。或你现在看到这个。
Or you saw this now.
或你现在看到这个。
is he's divisive but much more than that
他是分裂的，但远不止于此
he's immature he's incapable of growth okay but hey
他还不成熟，成长能力不足，但好吧
if in august he picks nikki haley to be his vp
如果他在八月把尼基·黑利选为副总统
then the media will be like he is a changed man
然后媒体会说他变了
he's learned his lessons he's willing to let go
他学会了经验，愿意放下怨恨
of grudges he's willing to listen he now has empathy
他愿意倾听，已有同理
therefore
于是
he should be president okay do you understand
他应该当选总统，明白吗？
but then
然后
what happens is the suburbs switch over to trump
发生的是郊区投票给特朗普
and then he wins so
于是他赢了
if he picks nikki haley in august
如果他在八月挑选尼基·黑利
he will win okay i'm not completely sure
他会赢，嗯，我不完全确定
that he will pick nikki haley i think that
他会挑选尼基·黑利，我想是这样
this is his best strategic move okay but
这是他最好的战略举措，嗯
trump is not really predictable all right
特朗普并不太可预测，先说吧
and who he picks as vice president will give us a good clue as to how he will govern
他挑选谁做副总统，能给我们一个好线索，说明他会怎样执政
when he when he becomes president okay does that
他一旦当选总统，情况就会怎样呢
make sense all right now the question then
好像是这样，接下来是个问题
is okay who
是的，谁
is nikki haley and
是尼基·黑利
what will she do as vice president okay
她将会做什么副总统？
now what's important to understand about nikki haley is
现在，理解尼基·黑利的重要点是：
that when she left office when
她离任时……
she left washington dc political office in
她于2018年离开华盛市政治职务
2018 she had nothing in her bank account okay
她的银行账户里一分钱也没有
she had no money in her bank account now
她的银行账户里现在也没有钱
she has 10 million dollars in her bank account
她的银行账户里有一千万美元
and she lives in a five million dollar mansion
她住在一栋价值五百万美元的豪宅里
so where
于是呢？
did she get this money okay she got her
她拿到这笔钱了吗？好的，她拿到了。
she got this money mainly for
她拿这笔钱主要是为了
an organization called united against
一个名为“United Against”的组织
a nuclear
一个核
iran okay and
伊朗，好吧
this organization's primary purpose is
该组织的主要目的在于
to create conflict between the united states and
制造美国与……之间的冲突
iran okay they they go
伊朗，好吧，他们去
against any companies or individuals who
对任何公司或个人
support iran united states who
支持伊朗的美国人做生意
does business with iran okay they
他们与伊朗做生意
are a very anti
是非常……的
-iranian organization one of
……伊朗组织之一
their main donors his name is sheldon alderson
他们的主要捐赠者是谢尔顿·阿尔德森
and
和
sheldon alderson is an extremely pro -israel business person
谢尔顿·阿尔德森是一位极其亲以色列的商人
okay he owns a lot of casinos okay
他拥有许多赌场
so mgm sands uh he's he's a billionaire
于是mgm sands，他是亿万富翁
and what's interesting about sandal uh sandal alderson he's dead okay but
以及关于沙龙·阿尔德森的有趣之处，他已经去世，但……
he was the main patron of a man named sheldon alderson
他是名为谢尔顿·阿尔德森的人的主要赞助者……
he's the main political patron and financial donor to benjamin netanyahu okay
他是本杰明·内塔尼亚胡的主要政治赞助者和财务捐赠者。
he is the main political patron
他是本杰明·内塔尼亚胡的主要政治赞助者
and financial donor to benjamin netanyahu
以及财务捐赠者
so sheldon alderson supports both netanyahu
于是谢尔顿·阿尔德森同时支持内塔尼亚胡
and supports this organization called united against a nuclear iran
并支持一个名为“联合对抗核伊朗”的组织
and united against a nuclear iran hired um nikki haley
并联合对抗核伊朗雇佣了尼基·海利
and paid a lot of money okay that's the first thing second thing is
并支付了大量资金，第一件事，第二件事是
that in iran there's a lot of people who support iran and in 2019 she got a job
在伊朗有很多支持伊朗的人，2019年她得到了一份工作
with boeing boeing is a weapons manufacturer they make airplanes
她加入了波音公司，波音是一家武器制造商，他们生产飞机
but they mainly make bombs and missiles okay so
但他们主要生产炸弹和导弹
they love war she sat on the board of boeing an extremely prestigious job
他们热爱战争，她担任波音董事会席位，极具声望的职位
and she was paid three hundred thousand u.s dollars just to sit on the board
她获得三十万美元的报酬，仅仅是坐在董事会席上
and do nothing okay she has
然后她什么也没干
also given speeches at an organization called christianism there's a
也在基督教组织的演讲中出现了一个
series of
系列的
uh uh uh uh uh uh uh uh uh
呃呃呃呃呃呃呃呃
uh uh uh uh Kingdom of Heaven and therefore
呃呃呃呃王国之天，故此…
they want as much conflict in the Middle East as possible.
他们想在中东尽可能多的冲突。
So all this is telling us is
所以这一切都在告诉我们
that if Nikki Haley becomes vice president,
如果尼基·海利成为副总统
her main responsibility
她的主要职责是
will be to agitate for war against Iran.
将会动员发动对伊朗的战争。
She will be the one in
她将是那位在……的白宫人物
the White House pushing for war in Iran,
在白宫推动伊朗战争的那个人
escalating tensions in Iran.
伊朗局势持续升温。
So Nikki Haley.
于是尼基·海利。
What's also interesting is
还有一点有趣的事是。
in January 2019
2019年1月
basically the primary is over.
基本上初选结束。
Trump has won everything. But in January 2019.
特朗普已赢得一切。但在2019年1月。
even after Trump won,
即便特朗普赢了，
Haley was able to raise more money than Trump.
海利也筹集了比他更多的钱。
So Haley got about 12 million dollars from donors,
于是海利从捐赠者那里筹得约1200万美元。
Trump gets 11 million dollars.
特朗普筹得1100万美元。
Okay? And
好的？还有
the only explanation for this is these donors knew
这唯一的解释是这些捐赠者知道
that Haley would not become president,
那海利不会成为总统，
she could not be Trump, but
她也不是特朗普，但
they're trying to position her to be
他们正把她定位为
his vice president by making her stay in the race
让她留在竞选中，成为他的副总统
and giving her as much publicity as possible.
并尽可能给她宣传。
In fact, even though she dropped out of the race,
事实上，即使她退出竞选，
she's still getting about 25%
她仍然获得约25%
to 33% of all Republican votes, okay? So
到33%的全部共和党票数，好的？
she comes across as an extremely popular establishment figure.
她给人的印象是极受欢迎的建制派人物。
So this is the the Haley Haley Haley Haley
于是这就是哈利的哈利哈利哈利。
Haley Haley
哈利 哈利
Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley
哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利
哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利
Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley
哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利
Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley
哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利
Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley
哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利 哈利
Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley Haley
哈利
Haley Haley
Haley or Trump has slight advantage,
哈利或特朗普略占优势，
okay? Trump can basically seal the victory
好的？如果他挑选尼基·哈利做副总统，特朗普基本能锁定胜利，
if he picks Nikki Haley to be his vice president,
if he picks Nikki Haleyto be his vice president,
because Nikki Haley will turn the suburbs to him
因为尼基·哈利会把郊区强力交给他
very strongly, and it's the suburbs that
而郊区正是决定美国选举的关键
basically decide US elections.
basically decideUS elections.
And as vice president,
作为副总统，
what she will be doing is advocating for war against Iran,
她将要做的就是倡导对伊朗的战争，
which means that she's on the payroll
这意味着她已被列入名单中
of anti -Iranian forces in the United States.
在美国的反伊朗势力中。
Okay? So, any questions?
好的？那还有问题吗？
Anything you're not clear about right now?
现在你还有不明白的地方吗？
What if she holds a grudge against Trump?
如果她对特朗普怀有怨恨呢？
Okay, so Jack asked a great question, okay?
好的，杰克提出了一个很好的问题，明白吗？
He's like, what if Haley holds a grudge and says no, right?
他是这么说的：如果哈利对他有怨恨并且说不，怎么样？
And quite honestly, she has been asked in the past,
而且说实话，她曾被问过，
are you willing to serve as Trump's vice president?
你愿意当特朗普的副总统吗？
And she's like, no, because he's a divider.
她回答说，愿意，因为他是个分裂者。
He's divisive, and we need to move on from Trump, okay?
他是分裂的，我们需要从特朗普身上走开，明白吗？
All right. Do you guys remember in class,
好的。你们记得在课堂上，
when we studied Trump, very closely, his personality?
当我们细细研究特朗普，他的个性格吗？
We looked at his days in the WWE, okay?
我们回顾了他在WWE的日子，行吗？
And there was a scene where Vince McMahon,
随后出现了一个场景，Vince McMahon，WWE的老板，亿万富翁，挑战特朗普。
the owner of WWE, a billionaire, challenges Trump
to a fight, right?
转成一场斗争，行吗？
Well, guess what, guys? Politics is the same thing.
好，猜猜吧，伙计们？政治就是一样的事。
It's all theater, okay?
全是戏剧，明白吗？
Politics is theater. What Nikki Haley
政治是戏剧。尼基·黑利
and Donald Trump are doing is pretending to be bitter enemies,
和唐纳德·特朗普正在假装成对手，
so that their reconciliation will be
以便他们的和解能出现。
so dramatic. You understand?
好戏剧。你明白吗？
So, Nikki Haley served under Trump in the first administration,
于是，尼基·黑利在特朗普第一届任期服役，
okay? So, from 2016 to 2018,
好？于是，从2016到2018，
she was used to being a fighter. She was used to being an ambassador for Trump.
她习惯了当斗士。她习惯了当特朗普的使者。
And everyone says that the two got along really well.
大家都说两人相处得很不错。
In fact,
事实上，
Trump was considering having her be his VP,
特朗普正在考虑让她担任副总统
running mate, in 2020.
2020年，他是竞选搭档。
He was thinking of dropping Mike Pence and putting her on the ticket, okay?
他想把麦克·佩恩换掉，放上她，行吗？
So, the two of them together actually have a great rapport.
于是，两人合在一起真的相处得很好。
The two respect each other.
两人互相尊敬。
They get along very well, okay? So, that's the first thing.
他们相处得很好，行吗？所以，这就是第一件事。
Second thing is that,
第二件事是……
the thing to know about very
关于非常成功的政治家的第一件事是
successful politicians is they are first
成功的政治家首先是
and foremost opportunists.
而且是最主要的机会主义者。
They have no ideas.
他们没有主张。
They have no principles.
他们没有原则。
All they care about is political power, right?
他们只关心政治权力，对吧？
So, why would Nikki Haley agree to be Vice President?
那么，尼基·海利为什么会同意做副总统？
Why? Because
为什么？因为
there's one step away from the presidency.
离总统一步之遥。
presidency, do you understand? If anything happens to Trump, she's president.
总统，明白吗？只要特朗普有事，她就能当选。
And in four years time, she can run as
四年后，她就能竞选。
the Republican nominee for the presidency.
共和党总统候选人。
Does that make sense? So that's the thing you need to know about politicians.
这有道理吗？这就是你需要知道的关于政治家的事。
All they care about is political power.
他们只关心政治权力。
They will do anything to achieve political power.
他们会不择手段争取政治权力。
They will sell their own mother to achieve political power.
他们会卖掉自己的母亲以争取政治权力。
But it's the same thing for rich people.
但这对富人来说也是同样的事。
Rich people love money.
富人爱钱。
They will do anything to get money.
他们会不择手段争取钱。
Sell their own mother, fine.
卖掉自己的母亲也行。
Also, celebrities, famous people, right?
还有，明星、名人，对吧？
All they care about is fame. So, do you understand, Jack?
他们只在乎名声。所以，你明白了吗，杰克？
Any more questions?
还有别问吗？
Is this clear to you guys?
这句话你们明白了吗？
Is there anything you're not clear about?
还有什么不明白的吗？
I'll explain further.
我再解释一下。
Is there anything that
有什么可以
Biden could do before the election
拜登在选举前可以做的事
to have an advantage over Trump?
来占据优势于特朗普？
Okay, so Jack asked a great question, okay?
好的，杰克刚刚问了个好问题，听着？
Well, listen. Like,
嗯，听着。像是，我只要读新闻就能算出来，对吧？
I can figure this out just by reading the news, right?
I can figure this out justby reading the news, right?
Biden has an amazing team of extremely well -paid,
拜登拥有一支极其高薪、专业、经验丰富的战略团队与他合作。
professional, experienced strategists working with him.
他们对此了如指掌，能洞察一切。
They know this. They can see what's going on.
他们知道这一点，能看清局势。
So, what can Biden do to
那么拜登能做什么来应对特朗普的策略或民调呢？
counter Trump's strategy or the polls, okay?
答案是这样的：如果你看看2020年，…】
And the answer is this. If you look at 2020,
everyone thought
大家都认为
that Biden could not get the nomination, okay?
拜登能否获得提名？
Why? Because he lacks charisma.
为什么？因为他缺乏魅力。
Nobody really likes him, okay?
没人真喜欢他，行吗？
So, when Biden goes to school, he's not going to get the nomination.
于是，拜登去学校时，他还没拿到提名。
He's going to speak. There's no one there to listen to him.
他会发言。那里没人听他说。
He's boring, and he has no ideas, and he's old.
他很无聊，没想法，老了。
I mean, Biden ran for president two times before, and he lost both times.
我说，拜登以前跑两次总统，两个都输了。
And the reason why is he's not charismatic, and
原因是他不具魅力，且
he has no ideas, okay?
他没有想法，行吗？
But Biden's like, nope, I'm going to stay in the race because I believe I can win.
但拜登说：不，我会继续参选，因为我相信能赢。
And you ask him, Biden, what is your strategy?
你问他，拜登，你的策略是什么？
What is your reasoning going forward?
接下来你会怎么推理？
I don't know. I'm going to win, okay?
我不知道，我会赢，行吗？
So, if we were discussing this in 2020,
于是，如果我们在2020年讨论这个，
in May and June,
在五月和六月，
I would be like, Biden has no chance, okay?
我会说：拜登没机会，行吗？
Because Trump's going to go out there and
因为特朗普会去那里…
give speeches to 100,000 people, and
给十万人演讲，随后他们会爱上他，随后去投票，行吗？
they're going to love him, and they're going to go and vote for him, okay?
拜登演讲，大家全都睡着。
Biden gives a speech, everyone falls asleep.
Biden gives a speech,everyone falls asleep.
And under the debate stage,
在辩论阶段，
Trump will destroy Biden, okay?
特朗普会把拜登打败，行吗？
So, I was sure that
于是，我确信
in May, April 2020,
五月，四月2020年，
Biden had no chance.
拜登没有机会。
But then what happened? Hey, the George Floyd protest happened.
然后发生了什么？嘿，乔治·弗洛伊德示威发生了。
So all these young people who didn't really like Biden,
于是这些年轻人，之前不太喜欢拜登，
they were now galvanized to go vote for him.
他们现在被激励去投票给他。
All these black people, all these suburban voters,
这些黑人、郊区选民，
they wanted Biden to win because they thought Trump was divisive, okay?
他们想拜登赢，因为觉得特朗普分裂，行吗？
And then what happened? The pandemic happened.
然后发生了什么？疫情来了。
So, Trump couldn't go out to debate.
于是特朗普没能出场辩论。
Trump couldn't go out to campaign anymore.
特朗普再也没法外出竞选了。
You understand? Biden could just sit in his basement
你明白吗？拜登可以在他地下室里坐着不动，没错吧？
and do nothing, right?
and do nothing,right?
Do you understand? So,
你明白吗？于是，
unfortunately, Biden learned the wrong lessons from 2020.
不幸的是，拜登从2020年学到了错误的经验。
The lesson that he learned in 2020 is that, hey,
他在2020年学到的经验是，嘿，
if I just sit in my basement all day and make no mistakes,
如果我整天坐在地下室里不犯错，我的代理人，民主党国会，都会说：我就是民主党主席。
my surrogates, the Democratic Congress, they're going to be like, oh, I'm going to be the president of the Democratic Party.
希拉里·克林顿、比尔·克林顿、巴拉克·奥巴马，…
Hillary Clinton, Bill Clinton, Barack Obama,
Hillary Clinton, BillClinton, Barack Obama,
they'll go out and give speeches for me.
他们会出来为我演讲。
They'll fire up the base. And I'll win because
他们会点燃基础。于是我赢了，因为
I'm not Trump, okay?
我不是特朗普，明白吗？
That is the entire Biden strategy.
那就是完整的拜登策略。
I'm not Trump.
我不是特朗普。
Okay? The problem with this idea is,
好吧？这个想法的难点是，
okay, in 2020,
好的，2020年，
the American people, the American people, people had four years of Trump,
美国人民，美国人民，四年特朗普后，
and they know he sucks, okay?
他们知道他很糟，明白吗？
The problem now is the American people have seen four years of Biden,
现在的问题是美国人民已经看到了四年的拜登，
and Biden sucks as well, okay?
拜登也很糟，明白吗？
And so, it's a question like, who sucks more,
于是问题是，谁更糟呢？
Biden or Trump, okay?
拜登还是特朗普，明白吗？
So, in other words, people are not going to come out to vote
于是换句话说，选民不会去投票
because they think both suck,
因为他们觉得两者都糟
and which means that the party with equality, right?
并且这意味着拥有平等的党派，对吧？
The only coalition with a base that feels more strongly about the issues is going to come out to vote, okay?
唯一那支基底更强烈关注议题的联盟才会去投票，对吗？
And what we know is that
我们已知的就是……
the Republican coalition
共和党联盟
of rural voters, conservatives, Christians,
乡村选民、保守派、基督徒、白人选民
white voters,
they feel much more passionately about Trump than the Democratic coalition feels about Biden.
他们对特朗普的热情远超民主党联盟对拜登的热情。
Okay? Does that make sense? So, unfortunately,
好吧？这样说对吗？所以不幸的是，
the answer is that Biden is only going to vote.
答案是拜登只会投票。
Biden has no strategy going forward because he didn't have a strategy going forward in 2020.
拜登前进没有策略，因为他在2020年也没有前进的策略。
And he won in 2020, so why can't the same thing happen in,
他在2020年赢了，那为什么今年也能这么做呢？
same thing happen this year, right?
同样的事今年也能发生吗？
And unfortunately, because Biden's so old, he's 81,
而且不幸的是，拜登年事已高，81岁，
he doesn't have the energy to change the way he is.
他没有精力去改变自己的状态。
You understand? It's much easier for him to sit around
你明白了吗？他坐在那儿更容易，然后祈祷那样的方式。
and pray the way that
and pray the waythat
I'm not Trump will deliver another election than it is for him to go out
我不认为特朗普会再赢一次选举，随后再去改变自己。
and change who he is. He can't change who he is.
他自己也没法再改变自己。
Okay? Does that make sense?
好的？这样说通吗？
Okay, but that's a great question, all right?
好的，但这确实是个好问题，没错吧？
Any more questions before?
还有问题吗？
Okay. Okay, so again,
好的。好的，再说一次，
I am not sure
我不确定
who will win this year, okay?
谁会在今年赢得比赛，好吗？
I think it's Trump. I'm not sure that
我觉得是特朗普。我不确定尼基·海利会是他的副总统。
Nikki Haley will be his vice president.
我只是猜测。所以问题是我们为什么要这么做？
I'm just making a guess. So the question then is why are we doing this?
And the answer is this. We try to think.
答案就是这样。我们先想一想。
We have to build an analytical model, right, of how the world works.
我们得构建一个分析模型，来说明世界是怎样运作的。
And the only way we know if this model works or not is by making predictions
检验模型是否有效的唯一办法，就是做出预测。
and testing it against reality.
并用它与现实检验。
Okay? So you know what?
好吧？那你知道什么？
It's possible that in August,
有可能在八月，
Trump will pick someone else okay?
特朗普会选其他人吗？
Possibly someone named JD Vance okay?
可能是叫J.D. Vance的人吗？
The only thing you need to know about JD Vance is he's very loyal to Trump okay?
关于J.D. Vance你只需要知道的一点是他对特朗普非常忠诚。
It's possible he picks JD Vance okay?
有可能他选J.D. Vance吗？
I think he'll pick Nikki Haley. I often actually...
我觉得他会选Nikki Haley。我经常这样想……
I often think that there's a very good chance he picks JD Vance as well okay?
我经常认为他很可能也会选J.D. Vance，好吗？
But I'll make the bet that he picks Nikki Haley.
我会押注他会选Nikki Haley。
So it's possible in August he does not pick Nikki Haley,
于是，8月他可能不选Nikki Haley，
he picks J.D. Vance or someone else instead.
他可能选J.D. Vance或其他人。
It's also possible that in November Trump loses.
也有可能在十一月特朗普落败。
Well that's fine because if I'm wrong,
好吧，没问题，如果我错了，
then what I do is I go back to this analysis
我就回到这份分析里去
and I make changes to this analysis
我对这份分析做了调整
so that it's much more reflective and accurate.
使其更具反思性和准确性。
Does that make sense?
这有道理吗？
And that's how we try to think critically about the world.
这就是我们尝试用批判性思维看世界的方式。
By building analytical models that we can then test against reality
通过构建可随后对照现实检验的分析模型
and then based on what happens in reality,
并根据现实中发生的事来调整
we can go and refine our analytical model.
我们可以去细化我们的分析模型。
Any questions? Okay, so
还有问题吗？
next week we discuss the war in Iran,
下周我们讨论伊朗的战争，
okay? Because if you look at this,
好的？因为如果你看这个，
again if Nikki Haley becomes the vice president,
再次，如果尼基·海利成为副总统，
it is very likely she will agitate for war against Iran.
很可能她会发动对伊朗的战争。
And Trump will go along, okay?
好，特朗普也会跟着走，好的？
And if that's the case, then
如果是这样的话，接下来
we need to understand how America will fight the war and how Iran will respond.
我们需要了解美国将如何打这场战争，以及伊朗会如何回应。
And that's what we will do next week, okay? Thank you.
那就是我们下周要做的事，好的？谢谢。